<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nokia | NokiaMan]]></title>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/categories/nokia/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-07T23:37:27+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[manojlds]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nokia follows you on twitter to support a new service]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/12/07/nokia-follows-you-on-twitter-to-support-a-new-service/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T23:17:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/12/07/nokia-follows-you-on-twitter-to-support-a-new-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nokia has come up with an <a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2012/12/06/another-reason-to-follow-us-on-twitter/">innovative new service called TweetSender</a>. Basically, the service lets you sign up one or more Nokia devices ( that you probably own ) and it then sends you a DM ( direct message ) on Twitter when there are information available about the devices - like software updates, apps etc.</p>

<p>This is a pretty innovative idea in my opinion. You tend to miss updates on Twitter, and this makes sure you get pertinent updates about your device directly from Nokia.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/nokiatwitter.png" title="NokiaTwitter" ></p>

<p>There is, what I consider, a huge flaw in this. Not in the service exactly or what it tries to achieve, but with how it achieves this functionality. Once you sign up for this, the official @Nokia twitter account starts following!</p>

<p>As much as a ego boost it may be for me to be followed by @Nokia, I wonder why they couldn't have use some other account for this purpose, like, say @TweetSender, etc. I am not an expert on Twitter terms and API, but I think it should have been possible. Why would you have your main Twitter account follow everyone who wants to be followed?</p>

<p>Neverthless, this is a good service from Nokia and I am sure many will benefit from this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nokia Here is here]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/nokia-here-is-here/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T23:15:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/nokia-here-is-here</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love Nokia Maps. I pitied the users of mobile devices who couldn't use Nokia Maps. I felt sorry for them. More so for people with an iPhone running iOS 6.</p>

<p>Nokia Maps is a good brand. Nokia itself is a good brand. It might not be all that popular in US, but Nokia is well known throughout the World. It has consistently been the most trusted brand here in India and elsewhere. Even when the iOS maps fiasco happened, Nokia Maps started getting good amount of attention.</p>

<p>And Nokia Maps was previously called Ovi Maps. Nokia was trying to build a platform with the Ovi name - Ovi store, Ovi Music etc. But it didn't work and Nokia switched to Nokia branding. Nokia Fans rejoiced.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/nokia-here-maps-app.png" title="NokiaHere" ></p>

<p>But now, out of the blue, HERE is here. And we must ask - Why Nokia, why????? And the highlight is that the services are now available on virtualy all platforms. Again, why????</p>

<p>Nokia Maps is (was) Nokia's powerful weapon. It had good data. Good navigation features. Good features. And it has saved me thousands of time over the last many years. It is one of the main reasons why I buy a Nokia and a Nokia alone ( not exactly the only reason, but it is a main factor.) All that Nokia has to do is to build the Nokia Maps brand. Make users of Android and especially iOS realize what they are missing and make them switch to Nokia devices. I don't see how opening it up to every platform actually helps Nokia sell more devices. It might help improve the maps, but what about device sales?</p>

<p>People are not going to switch from iPhone to a Lumia because the latter has Nokia maps, er, HERE. Because the same maps is available for the iPhone too. Even if it is a HTML5 equivalent ( for now or forever?), if the maps are good, then people will stay with their device and if it is not good, it will only spoil Nokia's image.</p>

<p>So, why Nokia, why?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 things you didnt know about the Nokia Lumia 920 - Comments]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/10-things-you-didnt-know-about-the-nokia-lumia-920-comments/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T18:02:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/10-things-you-didnt-know-about-the-nokia-lumia-920-comments</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Review of <a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2012/11/10/10-things-you-didnt-know-about-the-nokia-lumia-920/">10 things you didn't know about the Nokia Lumia 920</a></p>

<p><blockquote><p>1. Zirkonium camera deco and side buttons</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I definitely didn't know about this. Nice to see Nokia continue to innovate in the hardware front.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>2. Perfectly synchronized floating lens tech</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Having owned phones like N73, N8 I have been pretty disappointed with the camera on my current Lumia 800. While the camera on the Lumia 800 might put phones from other manufacturers to shame, it is far behind the camera on the N8, which I believe is the best camera on any smartphone ( I don't consider the 808 PureView here for obvious reasons.) So, I am delighted to see that the Lumia 920 might offer a camera that promises to be the evolutionary equivalent of the camera on N8 and the N73.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>3. NFC integrated into wireless charging stand</p></blockquote></p>

<p>To me, the wireless charging itself is a gimmick. I still don't get what's the real value in it, atleast as of now.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>4. Higher-powered flash</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Again, I miss the Xenon flash on the N8 ( actually, I still use my N8 along with my Lumia 800). Why can't Nokia compare with the flash on N8 rather than just present vague statements like this?</p>

<p><blockquote><p>5. Personal music equalizer</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Ok, moving on... ( I still feel like my N73 had the best music quality of all my phones. It had great presets as well.)</p>

<p><blockquote><p>6. Automatic photo upload</p></blockquote></p>

<p>The Lumias already do it. Nothing unknown. Weak point this.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>7. Better Facebook personalization</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>8. Your own Lumia 920 rooms</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I have really liked the Facebook and social integration on Windows Phone and it is nice to see the incremental improvements in this front. The N8, and of course, other Symbian devices, seriously lacked in this front.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>9. Bluetooth voice commands</p></blockquote></p>

<p>This seems pretty standard.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>10. You can photograph the web</p></blockquote></p>

<p>This one is really useful and nice to see that Windows Phone has it by default. I am sure I will use screenshots on the phone a lot.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
