<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[NokiaMan]]></title>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-07T23:37:27+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[manojlds]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nokia follows you on twitter to support a new service]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/12/07/nokia-follows-you-on-twitter-to-support-a-new-service/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T23:17:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/12/07/nokia-follows-you-on-twitter-to-support-a-new-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nokia has come up with an <a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2012/12/06/another-reason-to-follow-us-on-twitter/">innovative new service called TweetSender</a>. Basically, the service lets you sign up one or more Nokia devices ( that you probably own ) and it then sends you a DM ( direct message ) on Twitter when there are information available about the devices - like software updates, apps etc.</p>

<p>This is a pretty innovative idea in my opinion. You tend to miss updates on Twitter, and this makes sure you get pertinent updates about your device directly from Nokia.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://nokiaman.github.com/images/nokiatwitter.png" title="NokiaTwitter" ></p>

<p>There is, what I consider, a huge flaw in this. Not in the service exactly or what it tries to achieve, but with how it achieves this functionality. Once you sign up for this, the official @Nokia twitter account starts following!</p>

<p>As much as a ego boost it may be for me to be followed by @Nokia, I wonder why they couldn&#8217;t have use some other account for this purpose, like, say @TweetSender, etc. I am not an expert on Twitter terms and API, but I think it should have been possible. Why would you have your main Twitter account follow everyone who wants to be followed?</p>

<p>Neverthless, this is a good service from Nokia and I am sure many will benefit from this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When will the Nokia Lumia 920 be available in India?]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/when-will-the-nokia-lumia-920-be-available-in-india/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-18T23:26:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/when-will-the-nokia-lumia-920-be-available-in-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There have been reports going around the <a href="http://www.thinkdigit.com/Mobiles-PDAs/Nokia-Lumia-920-not-launching-in-India_11380.html">Nokia Lumia 920 may not be available in India any time soon</a>, at the least, not in November.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://nokiaman.github.com/images/lumia920.png" title="lumia920" ></p>

<p>The Lumia 920 availability in India is completely in the dark at the moment. Reports that Nokia is diverting global stock to &#8220;more favourable&#8221; markets like the US and the UK and limiting the stock elsewhere is discouraging. This is pretty sad news for all Lumia fans in India hoping to get their hands on the 920.</p>

<p>While India has traditionally been a pretty strong market for Nokia ( and Nokia consistently being awarded the most trusted brand in India), other manufacturers like Samsung and HTC have eating away at its marketshare. It is disappointing even from this aspect that Nokia is not quickly releasing the widely anticipated Lumia 920 in India.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nokia Here is here]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/nokia-here-is-here/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T23:15:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/nokia-here-is-here</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love Nokia Maps. I pitied the users of mobile devices who couldn&#8217;t use Nokia Maps. I felt sorry for them. More so for people with an iPhone running iOS 6.</p>

<p>Nokia Maps is a good brand. Nokia itself is a good brand. It might not be all that popular in US, but Nokia is well known throughout the World. It has consistently been the most trusted brand here in India and elsewhere. Even when the iOS maps fiasco happened, Nokia Maps started getting good amount of attention.</p>

<p>And Nokia Maps was previously called Ovi Maps. Nokia was trying to build a platform with the Ovi name - Ovi store, Ovi Music etc. But it didn&#8217;t work and Nokia switched to Nokia branding. Nokia Fans rejoiced.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://nokiaman.github.com/images/nokia-here-maps-app.png" title="NokiaHere" ></p>

<p>But now, out of the blue, HERE is here. And we must ask - Why Nokia, why????? And the highlight is that the services are now available on virtualy all platforms. Again, why????</p>

<p>Nokia Maps is (was) Nokia&#8217;s powerful weapon. It had good data. Good navigation features. Good features. And it has saved me thousands of time over the last many years. It is one of the main reasons why I buy a Nokia and a Nokia alone ( not exactly the only reason, but it is a main factor.) All that Nokia has to do is to build the Nokia Maps brand. Make users of Android and especially iOS realize what they are missing and make them switch to Nokia devices. I don&#8217;t see how opening it up to every platform actually helps Nokia sell more devices. It might help improve the maps, but what about device sales?</p>

<p>People are not going to switch from iPhone to a Lumia because the latter has Nokia maps, er, HERE. Because the same maps is available for the iPhone too. Even if it is a HTML5 equivalent ( for now or forever?), if the maps are good, then people will stay with their device and if it is not good, it will only spoil Nokia&#8217;s image.</p>

<p>So, why Nokia, why?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 things you didnt know about the Nokia Lumia 920 - Comments]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/10-things-you-didnt-know-about-the-nokia-lumia-920-comments/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T18:02:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/10-things-you-didnt-know-about-the-nokia-lumia-920-comments</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Review of <a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2012/11/10/10-things-you-didnt-know-about-the-nokia-lumia-920/">10 things you didn&#8217;t know about the Nokia Lumia 920</a></p>

<blockquote><p>1. Zirkonium camera deco and side buttons</p></blockquote>


<p>I definitely didn&#8217;t know about this. Nice to see Nokia continue to innovate in the hardware front.</p>

<blockquote><p>2. Perfectly synchronized floating lens tech</p></blockquote>


<p>Having owned phones like N73, N8 I have been pretty disappointed with the camera on my current Lumia 800. While the camera on the Lumia 800 might put phones from other manufacturers to shame, it is far behind the camera on the N8, which I believe is the best camera on any smartphone ( I don&#8217;t consider the 808 PureView here for obvious reasons.) So, I am delighted to see that the Lumia 920 might offer a camera that promises to be the evolutionary equivalent of the camera on N8 and the N73.</p>

<blockquote><p>3. NFC integrated into wireless charging stand</p></blockquote>


<p>To me, the wireless charging itself is a gimmick. I still don&#8217;t get what&#8217;s the real value in it, atleast as of now.</p>

<blockquote><p>4. Higher-powered flash</p></blockquote>


<p>Again, I miss the Xenon flash on the N8 ( actually, I still use my N8 along with my Lumia 800). Why can&#8217;t Nokia compare with the flash on N8 rather than just present vague statements like this?</p>

<blockquote><p>5. Personal music equalizer</p></blockquote>


<p>Ok, moving on&#8230; ( I still feel like my N73 had the best music quality of all my phones. It had great presets as well.)</p>

<blockquote><p>6. Automatic photo upload</p></blockquote>


<p>The Lumias already do it. Nothing unknown. Weak point this.</p>

<blockquote><p>7. Better Facebook personalization</p></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>8. Your own Lumia 920 rooms</p></blockquote>


<p>I have really liked the Facebook and social integration on Windows Phone and it is nice to see the incremental improvements in this front. The N8, and of course, other Symbian devices, seriously lacked in this front.</p>

<blockquote><p>9. Bluetooth voice commands</p></blockquote>


<p>This seems pretty standard.</p>

<blockquote><p>10. You can photograph the web</p></blockquote>


<p>This one is really useful and nice to see that Windows Phone has it by default. I am sure I will use screenshots on the phone a lot.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angry Birds Star Wars available for Windows 8 and Windows Phone 8]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/angry-birds-star-wars-available-for-windows-8/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T16:25:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/angry-birds-star-wars-available-for-windows-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest installment of Angry Birds, Angry Birds Star Wars is now available on the Windows Store and <a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-us/store/app/angry-birds/7f48eacf-1239-4877-88a4-abe9d3ddfad7">the Windows Phone 8 Store</a>. It is also expected that the new game, building upon the previously released Angry Birds Space game and with a Star Wars theme, might soon be available for WP7 phones like the Nokia Lumia 900 as well.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://nokiaman.github.com/images/angrybirds.png" title="AngryBirds" ></p>

<p>This is great news for Windows Phone 8 as the game was released along with the iOS and Android versions. The previous Angry Birds games either did not make their way into the Windows Phone store or were released long after the ones for iOS and Android were released. <a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2012/11/08/angry-birds-stars-edition-use-the-eggs-luke/">Nokia Conversations claim that Nokia has been working closely with Rovio</a> in order to bring out the game so close to WP 8 release.</p>

<p>Nokia has also managed to bring Angry Birds Roost, a Lumia exclusive app, which brings Angry Birds news, videos, etc.</p>

<p><img class="centre" src="http://nokiaman.github.com/images/angrybirdsstore.png" title="AngryBirdsStore" ></p>

<p>Release of Windows 8 and the shared kernel between Windows Phone 8 and Windows 8 could also mean greater developer uptake. If it is possible to share much of the code between the latest version of the World&#8217;s most used desktop operating system and the mobile OS, developers will be rushing in to develop apps and games for the platform. It is nice to see that this is already happening, with Rovio, who were slow to release the previous games to Windows devices, have quickly released the latest version to both Windows 8 and Windows Phone 8.</p>

<p>It is still disappointing that it will be <a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2012/11/08/angry-birds-stars-edition-use-the-eggs-luke/#comment-706271784">few weeks before this games is avaiable for Windows Phone 7.x users</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goods and the bads in Windows Phone 8 from app platform compatibility report]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/08/goods-and-the-bads-in-windows-phone-8-from-app-platform-compatibility-report/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-08T17:09:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/08/goods-and-the-bads-in-windows-phone-8-from-app-platform-compatibility-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft has released the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windowsphone/develop/jj206947(v=vs.105">App platform compatibility for Windows Phone</a>.aspx) for Developers to ensure compatibility of their apps from WP 7.x to WP 8.</p>

<p>This has provided me with some surprises, shocks and some pleasing changes.</p>

<p>Major shock for me was that FM radio has been disabled.</p>

<blockquote><p>Windows Phone 8 does not support the FM radio feature. If you use the FM radio API in a Windows Phone 8 app, a RadioDisabledException will occur.</p></blockquote>


<p>I hadn&#8217;t heard about this before and it was a huge disappointment. Sure I don&#8217;t use FM radio often. And there is always Internet radio. Some also use headsets like the Nokia BH-221 bluetooth headset that have FM-Radio, so lack of FM might not be a huge deal breaker. However, many do use FM on their phone, especially in the developing countries like India where data is still expensive. I still use my Nokia N8 as my FM transmitter, and that feature is being grossly missed in the Lumias. Now, the phones cannot even have FM radio, even if Nokia wants to add one.</p>

<p>Lets talk about a pleasing change now.</p>

<blockquote><p>When the user clicks an ad displayed in an app and clicks the back button twice in click succession, the app exits in wp8. In Windows Phone OS 7.1, the user would navigate through the apps back stack.</p></blockquote>


<p>This is a welcome change from the UX point of view. Many a times, I have to keep hitting the back button to come out of an app, like IE. It just keeps going back through the app and not to the previous app, as was my intention most of the times. I am still not clear if this brings up the previous app or just exits the current app. Will have to get a device and test it out.</p>

<p>When locking and locking the phone</p>

<blockquote><p>On Windows Phone OS 7.1, the video opens in the paused state and the image is visible. On Windows Phone 8, the video opens in the paused state but an empty black box is displayed in place of a frame from the paused video. In both cases, the user has to click Play to resume the video.</p></blockquote>


<p>I don&#8217;t know why this change was done. It is always nice to see the paused frame when coming back. Anyway, not a big deal.</p>

<p>Microsoft has also taken the extra step to ensure that apps built for Windows Phone 7 continue to work on 8 in the form of Quirk Modes</p>

<blockquote><p>For some features and APIs, rather than introducing a breaking change, the Windows Phone app platform provides a quirks mode that preserves the legacy behavior and applies it where appropriate, depending on the version of the Windows Phone the app was originally built and tested for. If the target version is Windows Phone OS 7.1, quirks mode either emulates the same behavior, or it uses the same code as Windows Phone OS 7.1. In other words, the app runs in Windows Phone 8 as it did when it was tested against the runtime it originally targeted.</p></blockquote>


<p>Microsoft has always been known for such attention to developer issues, and it is nice to see them continuing in that path.</p>

<p>There are however, many breaking changes, like the few mentioned above, but more developer centric. Developers of Windows Phone 7 apps and intending to develop on WP8 or wishing to have their apps continue to work on WP8 should definitely go through the list.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
