<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: symbian | NokiaMan]]></title>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/categories/symbian/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-11T00:21:43+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[manojlds]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I gravitate back to my Nokia N8]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/12/28/why-i-gravitate-back-to-my-nokia-n8/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-28T22:25:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/12/28/why-i-gravitate-back-to-my-nokia-n8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been using the Nokia N8 ever since it released over two years ago. Last year, I also started using a Nokia Lumia 800. As much as I liked the clean Windows Phone 7.x interface and the Lumia 800, at end of 2012 I find myself using my Nokia N8 again with my Lumia 800 gathering dust. At this point, with the Lumia 920 close to being released in India, I am strongly considering getting it. But in my heart I know that I will again gravitate towards my N8 sometime down the line, and probably end up using them both on and off.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/n8.jpg" title="nokia_n8" ></p>

<p>Why? That is the question I would like to answer for myself. There are certain aspect of the phone that make it amazing.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>1. 12 Megapixel Carl Zeiss Camera</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I am not sure any camera phone, Nokia or otherwise, can match the one on the N8. The 12 mpx camera, xenon flash and the Carl Zeiss lens cannot be found anywhere else. Even two years after its release, it remains amongst the top camera phones in the world. The 8mpx camera on the Lumia 800, though good, is not match. So is the camera interface. It is musch more rich in the Symbian phone than in the Windows Phone. I am sure the Lumia 920 will up the ante with PureView and what not, but I will have to see it to believe it.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>2. Amazing battery life</p></blockquote></p>

<p>The N8 still gives me about 2 days of battery life with modest data usage. The Lumia 800 barely lasts a day. To be fair, the Windows Phone has tighter integration to Twitter, Facebook, MS Exchange and other services than the N8. I like the Lumia 800 for it, but the ability of the N8 to last 2 days on a single charge is amazing. Many Symbian phone do that or better. Not many smartphones can live up to that.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>3. Easy file transfer, the Symbian openness and customization</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I miss the customization of Symbian in the Lumias. The ability to easily transfer files, use a file manager to browse files on the phone, amazing  themes, the homescreens, widgets are grossly missed. The Lumia 800 has its own lure with the WP7 interface with tiles. It is very simplistic, neat and fluid. But it is too simplistic for me. However, WP8 and WP7.8 once again raise the level with better tile interface amongst others. Should be interesting how that pans out in the 920.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>4. USB host, HDMI out, FM transmitter</p></blockquote></p>

<p>These are the cools features on the N8. Not present on many other phones and sorely missed. Ability to play songs via FM while driving your car is amazing. Tranfering files to / from a USB drive directly from the phone gives you a good feeling. HDMI is useful, though I did use it very little.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>5. Amazing Nokia Maps</p></blockquote></p>

<p>The Nokia maps on Symbian phones like the N8 is yet to be matched by the Lumias. Of course this will improve in the coming month, but for now, I use my N8 for all my navigation. The offline maps still remains the best.</p>

<p>There are other small things too, which make the N8 an amazing phone. If, and when, I feel safe and happy to switch from it to another phone, that phone will be one hell of a amazing phone. Hopefully, the Lumia 920 is that phone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
