<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tweetsender | NokiaMan]]></title>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/categories/tweetsender/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-11T00:21:43+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[manojlds]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nokia follows you on twitter to support a new service]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/12/07/nokia-follows-you-on-twitter-to-support-a-new-service/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T23:17:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/12/07/nokia-follows-you-on-twitter-to-support-a-new-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nokia has come up with an <a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2012/12/06/another-reason-to-follow-us-on-twitter/">innovative new service called TweetSender</a>. Basically, the service lets you sign up one or more Nokia devices ( that you probably own ) and it then sends you a DM ( direct message ) on Twitter when there are information available about the devices - like software updates, apps etc.</p>

<p>This is a pretty innovative idea in my opinion. You tend to miss updates on Twitter, and this makes sure you get pertinent updates about your device directly from Nokia.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/nokiatwitter.png" title="NokiaTwitter" ></p>

<p>There is, what I consider, a huge flaw in this. Not in the service exactly or what it tries to achieve, but with how it achieves this functionality. Once you sign up for this, the official @Nokia twitter account starts following!</p>

<p>As much as a ego boost it may be for me to be followed by @Nokia, I wonder why they couldn't have use some other account for this purpose, like, say @TweetSender, etc. I am not an expert on Twitter terms and API, but I think it should have been possible. Why would you have your main Twitter account follow everyone who wants to be followed?</p>

<p>Neverthless, this is a good service from Nokia and I am sure many will benefit from this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
