<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lumia 920 | NokiaMan]]></title>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/categories/lumia-920/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-18T23:41:16+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[manojlds]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When will the Nokia Lumia 920 be available in India?]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/when-will-the-nokia-lumia-920-be-available-in-india/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-18T23:26:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/when-will-the-nokia-lumia-920-be-available-in-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There have been reports going around the <a href="http://www.thinkdigit.com/Mobiles-PDAs/Nokia-Lumia-920-not-launching-in-India_11380.html">Nokia Lumia 920 may not be available in India any time soon</a>, at the least, not in November.</p>

<p><img src="/images/lumia920.png" title="lumia920" ></p>

<p>The Lumia 920 availability in India is completely in the dark at the moment. Reports that Nokia is diverting global stock to "more favourable" markets like the US and the UK and limiting the stock elsewhere is discouraging. This is pretty sad news for all Lumia fans in India hoping to get their hands on the 920.</p>

<p>While India has traditionally been a pretty strong market for Nokia ( and Nokia consistently being awarded the most trusted brand in India), other manufacturers like Samsung and HTC have eating away at its marketshare. It is disappointing even from this aspect that Nokia is not quickly releasing the widely anticipated Lumia 920 in India.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 things you didnt know about the Nokia Lumia 920 - Comments]]></title>
    <link href="http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/10-things-you-didnt-know-about-the-nokia-lumia-920-comments/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T18:02:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://nokiaman.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/10-things-you-didnt-know-about-the-nokia-lumia-920-comments</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Review of <a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2012/11/10/10-things-you-didnt-know-about-the-nokia-lumia-920/">10 things you didn't know about the Nokia Lumia 920</a></p>

<p><blockquote><p>1. Zirkonium camera deco and side buttons</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I definitely didn't know about this. Nice to see Nokia continue to innovate in the hardware front.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>2. Perfectly synchronized floating lens tech</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Having owned phones like N73, N8 I have been pretty disappointed with the camera on my current Lumia 800. While the camera on the Lumia 800 might put phones from other manufacturers to shame, it is far behind the camera on the N8, which I believe is the best camera on any smartphone ( I don't consider the 808 PureView here for obvious reasons.) So, I am delighted to see that the Lumia 920 might offer a camera that promises to be the evolutionary equivalent of the camera on N8 and the N73.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>3. NFC integrated into wireless charging stand</p></blockquote></p>

<p>To me, the wireless charging itself is a gimmick. I still don't get what's the real value in it, atleast as of now.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>4. Higher-powered flash</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Again, I miss the Xenon flash on the N8 ( actually, I still use my N8 along with my Lumia 800). Why can't Nokia compare with the flash on N8 rather than just present vague statements like this?</p>

<p><blockquote><p>5. Personal music equalizer</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Ok, moving on... ( I still feel like my N73 had the best music quality of all my phones. It had great presets as well.)</p>

<p><blockquote><p>6. Automatic photo upload</p></blockquote></p>

<p>The Lumias already do it. Nothing unknown. Weak point this.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>7. Better Facebook personalization</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>8. Your own Lumia 920 rooms</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I have really liked the Facebook and social integration on Windows Phone and it is nice to see the incremental improvements in this front. The N8, and of course, other Symbian devices, seriously lacked in this front.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>9. Bluetooth voice commands</p></blockquote></p>

<p>This seems pretty standard.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>10. You can photograph the web</p></blockquote></p>

<p>This one is really useful and nice to see that Windows Phone has it by default. I am sure I will use screenshots on the phone a lot.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
